Pachter, Henry M.; Papers ger071
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Henry M. Pachter (Heinz Paechter) Papers
1907-1987
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Pachter, Henry Maximilian, 1907-
ger071
8.49 cubic ft.
The collection contains Pachter's writings in history, economics, current events, the social sciences and other topics. The bulk of the collection consists of Pachter's published essayistic writings, both for journals (including numerous articles for Dissent) and for newspapers.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
The Henry M. Pachter Papers were donated to the University Libraries of the State University of New York by his widow, Hedwig Pachter, beginning in January 1982.
Biographical Sketch
Henry M. Pachter was born Heinz Maximilian Paechter on January 22, 1907 in Berlin, Germany. With the exception of a year at the University of Freiburg im Breisgau, Pachter received his formal education in Berlin and graduated from the University of Berlin in 1930, with a degree in history.
During his early years, Pachter became involved in the German youth movement and was a member of Der schwarze Haufen, but his socialist leanings soon led him to become disenchanted with the elitist nature of the group. By December of 1933, his association with socialist youth groups as well as publications in an underground leftist weekly, forced him to emigrate to the safety of Paris, where he remained for the next seven years. His future wife, Hedwig Rösler, whom he had met in 1928 in Berlin, joined Pachter in Paris in 1936. In France, Pachter became as a member of the Universitaire Populaire, often wrote under the pseudonym of Henri Rabasseire (Espagne Creuset Politique, 1938), and continued his association with both French and Spanish socialists. In September 1939, Pachter was interned in France, and began efforts to immigrate to the United States. Finally, having married Hedwig in 1940, they fled over the Pyrenees into Spain and eventually sailed from Portugal, arriving together in New York in April 1941.
Pachter quickly set about mastering the English language. During the early years in the United States Pachter worked as a consultant for both the Office of War Information (OWI) and the Office of Strategic Services (OSS), while still publishing articles in German as a U.S. correspondent for German newspapers and magazines, including the Deutsche Zeitung, Der Monat and Die Weltwoche. In 1945, he became editor of Economic Trends, where he continued until 1950.
In 1952, Pachter joined the History Department of the New School for Social Research as a lecturer, rose to professor and eventually chairman of the department. Pachter remained at the New School until 1967, and even served from 1963-1964 as acting director. In later years, Pachter also taught courses at Columbia University, the City College of the City University of New York and at Rutgers University in New Jersey.
Over the years, Pachter published hundreds of essays, as well as several full-length works on a broad range of subjects in history, economics and the social sciences. His main interest, as a proclaimed liberal social democrat and an avid anti-communist, was in explaining the meaning of socialism, in defense of the morality of socialism.
Henry Pachter died in New York on December 10, 1980.
Chronology of Events
Chronology of Events
1907 Born Heinz Maximilian Paechter on January 22 in Berlin, Germany; father Emil Paechter, mother, Helene Streisand Paechter. Belonged to Der schwarze Haufen, a German youth group.
1925-1926 Attended University of Freiburg im Breisgau, where he studied under Husserl and met Hannah Arendt, with whom he maintained a lifelong friendship.
1926-1930 Returned to Berlin; attended University of Berlin; also took classes from Karl Korsch at the Marxistische Arbeiterschule.
1930 Received his Ph. D. from the University of Berlin; joined the SPD (Socialist Party).
1930-1933 Worked as a free-lance writer and lectured at the Volks-Hochschule in Berlin.
1933-1940 Lived in Paris; member of Universitaire Populaire, Paris; active in the French resistance movement against Hitler; often published under the pseudonym Henri Rabasseire.
1936 Joined by Hedwig Rösler in Paris.
1939 Publication of book on the Spanish Civil War: Espagne Creuset Politique under the pseudonym Henri Rabasseire; interned briefly in France.
1940 Married Hedwig Rösler; fled France, travelling over the Pyrenees to Spain and eventually Portugal.
1941 April, emigrated to the United States on emergency visa.
1941-1945 Became a consultant for the Office of War Information (OWI); research associate for the Office of European Economic Research of the Office of Strategic Services (OSS).
1943 Birth of daughter Renée Vera.
1945-1950 Editor of Economic Trends.
1948 Became naturalized U.S. citizen.
1948-1964 Became U.S. correspondent for German newspapers, Deutsche Zeitung (Cologne), Der Monat (Berlin), Weltwoche (Zurich).
1951 Awarded Guggenheim grant for his work on recent changes in the social status of the intelligentsia, written for the Deutsche Zeitung.
1952-1967 Began as lecturer; became professor and chair of the Dept. of History, New School for Social Research.
1954 Became regular contributor to Dissent magazine; eventually co-editor.
1963-1964 Acting Dean of the New School for Social Research.
1965 Visiting professor at Columbia University.
1967-1976 Visiting Professor of History, City College of City University of New York.
1977-1980 Co-adjunct in political science at University College, Rutgers University.
1980 Died on December 10 in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The Henry M. Pachter Papers contain Pachter's writings in history, economics, current events, the social sciences and other topics. The bulk of the collection consists of Pachter's published essayistic writings, both for journals (including numerous articles for Dissent) and for newspapers. Also included are typescripts of two posthumously published full-length works, including his autobiography, Weimar Études. Typescript versions of several earlier autobiographical sketches, both in English and in German, as well as biographical tapes, are also present.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into seven series:
Series 1 - Biographical and Autobiographical Materials, 1907-1980, Undated
Series 2 - Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings, 1951-1980, Undated
Series 3 - Reviews of Pachter's Books, 1938-1984, Undated
Series 4 - Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others, 1982-1984, Undated
Series 5 - Articles Published in Journals, 1929-1987, Undated
Series 6 - Published Newspaper Articles, 1919-1980, Undated
Series 7 - Audio Tapes, Oversized Materials, 1984, Undated
Economics--Study and teaching.; History--Study and teaching.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; Germans--United States.; Jews--Germany--Berlin.; New York (N.Y.); Correspondence; Autobiographies; Reviews (document genre); Essays; typescripts; Articles; Clippings; Photographs; Pachter, Henry Maximilian, 1907-; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.: 1919-1997)
- Biographical and Autobiographical Materials, 1907-1980; Undated; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains autobiographical essays by Pachter, both in manuscript and published form, as well as writings about Pachter, including memorials by colleagues after his death in 1980. Also included in this series is a small amount of correspondence dealing with employment, and a few letters from contemporaries, including Thomas Mann and Martin Jay.
  - Documents, 1907-1975 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, list of publications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 2)
  - Photographs (2) of Pachter, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 3)
  - Book lists from Pachter's personal library, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 4)
  - Articles about Pachter, including lexicon and memorial articles, 1952-1984 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: appointments, 1952-1969 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, incl. L. from Martin Jay (1), Fritz Lamm, Thomas Mann (1), 1950s (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 7)
  - "Men in the Camp." Typescript, ca. 1940 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 8)
  - "April 1941, on board the Nyassa." Typescript (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 9)
  - "A dream, January 1946." Typescript, pc. (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 10)
  - "17. Juni 1953." Handwritten and typescript versions (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 11)
  - "16. Juli 1953. Tagebuch einer Heimkehr." Typescripts. (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 12)
  - "Schmerzliches Wiedersehen mit Berlin." Clipping., ca. 1954 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 13)
  - "Über den Tod. Fragmente." Handwritten and typewritten versions, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 14)
  - "Zorniger alter Herr nimmt Abschied vom Journalismus." Clipping., 28. January 1977 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 15)
  - "Growing Up Jewish in Weimar Germany." Clipping, 1980 June 29 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 16)
- Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings, 1951-1980; Undated; 2
  Arranged by language (German, then English) and alphabetically within languages.
  This series consists of typescript and manuscript versions of Pachter's essayistic writings, many unpublished.
  - "Ich melde mich zum Wort. Offener Brief an Hermann Kesten." Typescript, unpub, 1964 February 17 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 17)
  - "'John L.' Macht stets Geschichte." Typescript, unpub, 1955 October (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 18)
  - "Juden und Neger." Typescript, unpub, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 19)
  - "Kafka-tisch." Handwritten and typed versions, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 20)
  - "Kulturpolitik – Unkultur der Politik versus Politik der Unkultur. Typescript, unpub, ca. 1980 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 21)
  - "Die Kunst dem Volke – auch in Amerika." Typescript, unpub, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 22)
  - "Meinecke." Typescript, unpub, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 23)
  - "Mitbestimmungsrecht und Produktionskontrolle in Amerika." Typescript, unpub, ca. 1951 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 24)
  - "Sozialismus in Amerika." Typescript, unpub, 1961 June 14 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 25)
  - "Ueber das Problem der Zeit." Typescript, unpub, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 26)
  - Untitled handwritten and typed fragments, in German and English, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 27)
  - "A Letter to Some Jewish Friends." Typescript, ca. 1967 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 28)
  - "A Memoir of Walter Benjamin." Handwritten and typewritten versions, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 29)
  - "A Proposal to Surrender." Typescript, photocopy, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 30)
  - "An 'Inauthentic Jew's Reply to Jean-Paul-Sartre." Typescripts, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 31)
  - "Banausos Talks Back – A Project." Typescript, photocopy, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 32)
  - "Bonn Is Not WeiMarch" Typescript, photocopy, 1952 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 33)
  - "Café Groessenwahn." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 34)
  - "Can the Holocaust Be A Bore?" Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 35)
  - "Chomsky in His Bailiwick." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 36)
  - "Does Marxism Need a Foundation in Philosophy. Typescript, photocopy, 1978 November 16 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 37)
  - "Dreyfus Reviewed." Typescript, 1980 December (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 38)
  - "Erich Muehsam 1872-1934-1978." Typescript (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 39)
  - "History and Nature." Handwritten, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 40)
  - "History and Time." Typescript, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 41)
  - "In Memoriam Jacob Blauner." Typescript, photocopy, 1958 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 42)
  - "Isaac Newton 1642-1727." Typescript with notes, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 43)
  - "Jews in German Literature." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 44)
  - "Joseph Borkin, the Crime and Punishment of I.G. Farben." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 45)
  - "The Left in World Politics." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 46)
  - "The Much-Overdue Rehabilitation of Karl Kautsky, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 47)
  - "The Near East Crisis." Typescript, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 48)
  - "On an Essay of Meyer Shapiro." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 49)
  - "Politics, Values, and Political Science." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 50)
  - "The Realm of Thought." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 51)
  - "Realpolitik, Machtpolitik." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 52)
  - "The Rejection-Reflection Syndrome in Expressionism." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 53)
  - "Socialism and Democracy – Complementary or Contradictory?" Handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 54)
  - "Soviet Power in the Middle East, Israel, and the Jews." Typescript, 1967 November (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 55)
  - "Spain Revisited: Superficial Aspects of a Revolution." Typescript, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 56)
  - "Terrorism and Legitimacy – Bonn and WeiMarch" Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 57)
  - "Theory and Praxis – Observations on the work of Juergen Habermas." Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 58)
  - "Thirty Years Old – And in Berlin." Typescript, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 59)
  - "Toward a Marxist Theory of the State." Typescript, photocopy, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 60)
  - "Vigilantism in Germany and Austria during the 1920s." Typescripts, Undated (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 61)
  - Unpublished reviews. Typescript, photocopy, 1971 (Box 1 (2-Manuscripts and Typescripts of Essayistic Writings), Folder 62)
- Reviews of Pachter's Books, 1938-1984; Undated; 3
  This series contains reviews of eleven of Pachter's full-length works, including his early work written and published in French on the Spanish Civil War, Espagne Creuset Politique (1938), works in German and in English published after his emigration to the United States, as well as two volumes published posthumously, an autobiography Weimar Études (1982) and an essay volume Socialism in History (1984).
  - Espagne Creuset Politique, 1938 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 63)
  - The Axis Grand Strategy, 1942 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 64)
  - Nazi Deutsch, 1945 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 65)
  - Paracelsus. Magic into Science. Reviews, 1951 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 66)
  - Paracelsus. Magic into Science. Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 67)
  - The Third Reich, 1955 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 68)
  - Chruschtschow – Kennedy – Castro, 1963 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 69)
  - The Cuban Missile Crisis and Coexistence, 1964 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 70)
  - Weltmacht Rußland, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 71)
  - Modern Germany, 1979 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 72)
  - Weimar Études, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 73)
  - Socialism in History, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Reviews of Pachter's Books), Folder 74)
- Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others, 1982-1984; Undated; 4
  Arranged by work.
  Included in this series are two works published posthumously, Weimar Études and Socialism in History, as well as a second planned essay volume, History and Myth, edited by Stephen Eric Bronner, which remains unpublished. Also included in this series are typescripts and proofs of the translation by Hedwig Pachter of Hermann Vinke's The Short Life of Sophie Scholl.
  - Socialism in History. Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 1 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 75)
  - Socialism in History. Proofs, 1984 (Box 1 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 76-77)
  - Socialism in History. Parts I-II. Typescripts, 1983 (Box 1 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 78)
  - Socialism in History. Parts III-IV. Typescripts, 1983 (Box 1 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 79)
  - Socialism in History. Photographs used in the volume, 1984 (Box 1 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 80)
  - Weimar Études. Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 1 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 81)
  - Weimar Études. "Memoirs, first Ms." Handwritten, Undated (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 1)
  - Weimar Études. Early handwritten and typed versions, Undated (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 2-3)
  - Weimar Études. Introduction. Typescript, Undated (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 4)
  - Weimar Études. Typescripts, Undated (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 5-6)
  - Weimar Études. Page proofs, 1982 (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 7-9)
  - Vinke, Hermann.The Short Life of Sophie Scholl. Translation by Hedwig Pachter. Typescripts, 1984 (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 10-11)
  - Vinke, Hermann.The Short Life of Sophie Scholl. Proofs, 1984 (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 12-15)
  - Vinke, Hermann.The Short Life of Sophie Scholl. Unbound copy, 1984 (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 16)
  - Oppens, Kurt. "Emily Dickinson: Überlieferung und Prophete." Proofs, Undated (Box 2 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 17)
  - History and Myth. Planned volume of essays by Pachter, edited by Stephen Eric Bronner. Typescripts, Undated (Box 3 (4-Full-Length Works by Pachter and Others), Folder 1-2)
- Articles Published in Journals, 1929-1987; Undated; 5
  Arranged chronologically in German and English.
  This series contains copies of the essayistic writings of Pachter published in journals or as sections in books. Most are in published form, with a few accompanied by typescript versions. Also included in this section are Pachter's book and film reviews.
  - "Hände weg von Russland – Hände weg von China!" Photocopy, 1929 July 19 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 3)
  - "Der revolutionäre Internationalismus und der 'Renegat' Trotzky." Photocopy, 1929 November-1929 December (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 4)
  - "Kommunismus und Klasse." Photocopy, 1932 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 5)
  - "State and Nation in the Spanish War." Photocopy, 1938 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 6)
  - "Reflections on the Spanish Civil War." Photocopy, 1938 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 7)
  - "Recent Trends in the German Command Economy." Clipping, 1944 September (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 8)
  - "Washington, den 25. Mai 1946." Photocopy, 1946 June 15 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 9)
  - "Ike, Adlai und die Parteibosse." Clipping, 1952 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 10)
  - "Der Schmelztiegel arbeitet langsam."Clipping, 1953 January (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 11)
  - "Hundert Jahre nach 'Onkel Toms Hütte'." Clipping, 1953 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 12)
  - "Die neuen Männer in Washington." Clipping, 1953 March (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 13)
  - "Der letzte Jakobiner. Sozialismus war für Paul Fröhlich eine Idee und keine Taktik." Typescript, 1953 March 28 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 14)
  - "Reporter des Nichts." Clipping, 1953 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 15)
  - "Die Heimkehr des 'entfremdeten' Sohnes." Clipping, 1953 July 01 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 16)
  - "Angst als politische Mach." Clipping, 1953 September-1953 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 17)
  - "And Can There Be Peace?..." Clipping, 1954 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 18)
  - "Der 'böse Friedrich' geht um." Clipping, 1954 December (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 19)
  - "Fascist Propaganda and the Conquest of Power." Photocopy, 1955 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 20)
  - "McCarthy und die Katholiken." Clipping, 1955 March-1955 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 21)
  - "McCarthy und die Katholiken." Clipping, 1956 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 22)
  - "Der Fall Matthias." Clipping, 1956 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 23)
  - "Die Heiligen Rollen vom Toten Meer." Clipping, 1956 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 24)
  - "Some Aspects of Mass Culture." Alternate title: "In Defense of Television." Clipping, 1956 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 25)
  - "Amerikanische Gewerkschaften vor der Wahl.", 1956 July-August (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 26)
  - "Atomabrüstung und Atomdiplomatie." Clipping, 1957 November (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 27)
  - "Confessions of an Old-Timer." Photocopy, 1958 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 28)
  - "A Bewildering Debate." Clipping, 1958 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 29)